VICTOR CHUKWUEMEKA

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

anivictor.chukwuemeka.avc@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Developer with a Computer Science background and 1+ years of Freelance Experience.

Pair-programming and remote work aficionado. I specialize in ReactJS, NextJS, Ruby on Rails with Postgres, and Flutter. Looking to work on innovative ideas in a growth environment using the latest technologies to grow my skills and expertise and learn from other developers.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, NextJS, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Docker, Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Adaptability, Work Ethic, Teamwork, Mentoring, Communication, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving.

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full-stack Web Developer

Remote

October 2021 - July 2022

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building 15+ full-stack projects both independently and via pair programming.

Afia — Afia is an E-commerce web app where you can buy accessories. It has a stripe-supported card payment method.

• Built with: (Nextjs, sanity, stripe). | Live Demo

 $\underline{\text{Offlodge}}$ — Offlodge web app is a website for a gym business. It showcases the services it renders, there facilitators, and monthly plans suitable for there users.

• Built with: (React.js). Live Demo

Oracle booking app — This app allows users to book their favorite cars and purchase them. The app uses the API created in the Backend to add, select, and remove cars from the app. It makes it easy for users to add and remove their favorite cars from the list.

Built with: (React framework, deployed with Netlify & Rails framework, deployed with Heroku). | Live Demo

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

October 2021 - June 2022

- Mentored 3 junior web developers, and provided technical support through more than 15+ code reviews every week.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance by up to 5% every
- Provided advice and tips on maintaining motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE Remote Full-stack Web Development Program, Full-Time Remote

October 2021 - July 2022

- Spent 1500 hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

UNIVERSITY OF NIGERIA NSUKKA

B.sc, Computer Science

Enugu, Nigeria

September 2013 - September 2019

•	Introduction to Web Development, Introduction to Computer programming, Algorithm & Data Structures, Computer architecture